您现在应该熟悉原恒星的0级堆栈，尤其是我们的
quick look at what happens when you compile this code on a modern system.
Specifically with the stack cookies.
In this video I wanna develop a working exploit for it.
And believe me there are a few mountains we have to overcome.
Let’s get everybody quickly on track.
We have a simple buffer overflow vulnerability.
Originally the goal was to overflow into another variable to change the outcome of an if case.
但这已经不可能了，因为缓冲区现在放在变量之后-不是
before.
所以为了执行我们想要的if case，我们可能会溢出堆栈上的返回指针。
and simply redirect the code execution there.
但我们面临的一个问题是栈cookie，它包含三个随机字节，
checked before the function returns.
So in order to overflow the return pointer we would have to guess the cookie.
这意味着我们必须编写一个漏洞来一遍又一遍地执行目标，数以百万计
of times always guessing a stack cookie, and eventually we should get lucky.
但是在我们编写代码之前，让我们先开发利用，就像我们知道cookie一样
value.
This input really must be correct in order to work once we guess the correct cookie value.
So we have to debug this heavily.
让我们从用peda扩展打开gdb中的二进制文件开始，这使得它看起来
nicer and let’s just enter a loooot of characters in order to observe what happens.
Oops stack smashing detected.
We obviously want to ignore that.
So let’s set a breakpoint just before it would continue to __stack_chk_fail.
And then set eip to where it would have jumped to if the cookie was correct.
With a simple commands directive we can automate this everytime this breakpoint is hit.
Then continue.
Segmentation fault, that’s what we would expect.
Awesome.
哦…
返回时出现分段错误？
不是SegFault，因为我们将代码执行重定向到故障内存？
Look at the stack register.
esp指向无效的内存，因此当返回是构造时要查找返回
它试图跟踪esp指向的堆栈上的指针，这显然是在访问
invalid memory.
该死的…我们是怎么覆盖和修改堆栈指针的？
Let’s look again in the disassembly.
Down here just before the return.
So a value referenced by the base pointer, so a value on the stack is moved into ecx.
And then ecx -4 is calculated and that becomes the new stack pointer.
当我们看到这个函数的开头时，我们可以看到堆栈指针
-4 is stored in ecx and pushed on to the stack.
So the stack pointer is also saved on the stack.
我认为这是另一种缓解措施，因为在我们能够控制
return pointer, we first have to control the stack pointer.
起初这似乎不是问题，因为这意味着我们必须写一个
有效的堆栈指针并将其指向我们控制的缓冲区，然后返回将
take the return pointer we control in the buffer esp points to and we win.
But the issue is this modern system also has now ASLR.
We can see that if we re-enable aslr in the debugger and run it a few times.
Observe the esp value.
It’s always different.
I admit it’s not fully random, but it’s more bytes we would have to guess.
And to hit the cookie AND a valid stack address is starting to look bad.
假设我们知道堆栈的基本内存，这对我们有帮助吗？
There is even more here.
让我们重新运行程序，这次让我们看看esp指向何处并进行比较。
it to where the stack actually starts in memory.
当你这样做几次，你可以很快看到，特别是在不同的地方。
the stack really starts.
事实上，在
我们在esp指向的代码中使用的堆栈，以及
at the actual beginning of the stack memory area.
我认为这是另一种随机化值的方法，因为aslr只会随机化上面的值
parts of an address and this way also the lower bytes become unpredictable.
The game of exploitation has clearly changed.
There are more hurdles.
这是否意味着现在游戏结束了？
它不再是可利用的了？
我们不能用一个输入溢出来完成它？
Well.
there is a way.
But we have to get creative.
It’s not that easy anymore.
Ok so we know there is a cookie on the stack and we believe it’s bruteforceable.
So let’s assume we found the correct cookie, how do we go from there.
我们知道有效的堆栈指针存储在cookie之后，对吗？
The value of esp was saved at the beginning and restored here at the end again.
which means we can abuse that.
we don’t have to overwrite the whole pointer.
What if we just corrupt the first byte, so the lowest part of the address.
这意味着堆栈指针保持有效，但突然指向稍微不同的
stack memory.
也许我们可以让它稍微指向我们控制的缓冲区，这只是一点
lower than the stored esp value here.
然后我们恢复这个稍微偏离的值，返回值现在可以跟随地址指向
into valid stack memory and take the address there to return into.
如果它现在指向我们的缓冲区，我们可以控制我们想要返回的位置，我们可以
return into the if-case that prints our goal.
我们可以通过向缓冲区写入足够的数据来实现这一点，这样我们就可以在短时间内填满
从存储的堆栈指针，由于字符串以C中的零字节结尾，因此
将写入存储的esp值的最低部分，从而使其更小，
and when we are lucky it points into our buffer.
Let’s figure out the length.
So when we run it with the long input, we see that esp got overwritten with SSSS.
One byte is 4 lower than the others, thus became an O, which was cauysed by the ecx-4.
So this means we want to stop right before that.
And when we run it now, we see that esp ends now in fc.
所以它起作用了，因为我们预测堆栈中的最低部分将被0覆盖，
because of ecx-4, so 0 - 4 we end up with fc.
But as you can see, we didn’t get lucky, esp points to not our buffer.
但是，让我们重新运行它几次，并做同样的事情，在某个时刻，我们会很幸运，并且
now esp points to our buffer.
And when we now return we actually return into 4d4d4d4d, which is MMMM.
It worked.
实际上，堆栈上零填充的随机化使这项工作得以实现，因为在某些情况下
点地址的最低随机值将是正确的，因此0是正确的
amount of change so esp points into our buffer.
But you also see it’s not 100% reliable.
我们必须猜测cookie是正确的，然后希望esp随机化也很好。
to us.
But that’s fairly common so I hope that it’s common enough to still make it feasible.
So now all that we have to do is, put it together.
Let’s write a quick python script.
We import struct to convert the address to 4 byte strings.
Little lambda helper function for that.
然后我们简单地让我们的漏洞字符串用我们的地址填充缓冲区
want to return to.
We hope we can make esp point into this area.
然后是cookie值，稍后我们必须编写一些野蛮的逻辑
for.
Afterwards then comes 4 more bytes, and that’s it.
Then we print it.
Looks good.
You see the raw bytes are output with hexdump.
Write it to a file.
Let’s set a breakpoint at the cookie check to make sure the cookie is in the right place.
And then we can use the file as input in gdb.
First breakpoint was the cookie check.
And we can see we overwrite the cookie with COOK.
现在，当我按下Continue时，前面的另一个断点将命中并跳过tghe cookie
check and we reach the return.
Oh and look at that.
We got lucky with esp and esp actually points into our buffer.
When we now continue we return into the if-case that prints the modified string.
And there it is.
太神了！
So the exploit theoretically works.
All that is left, is the cookie bruteforcing.
Unfortunately that deserves it’s own episode again.
这只是编程，但做了它，你可以学到很多关于Linux的知识，而我不知道
wanna squeeze it in here.
Again, try to do that part yourself.
You could really learn alot.